Edwin Way Teale Papers 1981.0009
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series I: Writings, undated, 1799-1991
  - Subseries A: Books, undated, 1871-1991
    - Journey into Summer, (1960)
      - Chapter 30, "High Tundra" -Drafts, edited, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1075)
      - Chapter 31, "Summer Snow" -Correspondence, 1943, 1956-1958 (Box 20:, Folder 1076)
      - Chapter 31, "Summer Snow" -Notes, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1077)
      - Chapter 31, "Summer Snow" -Drafts, edited, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1078)
      - Chapter32, "The Sand Banners" -Clippings and pamphlets, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1079)
      - Chapter32, "The Sand Banners" -Notes, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1080)
      - Chapter32, "The Sand Banners" -Drafts, edited, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1081)
      - Chapter 33, "Land of the Five Summers" -Correspondence, 1958 (Box 20:, Folder 1082)
      - Chapter 33, "Land of the Five Summers" Clippings and pamphlets, 1938, 1956-1959 (Box 20:, Folder 1083)
      - Chapter 33, "Land of the Five Summers" -Notes, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1084)
      - Chapter 33, "Land of the Five Summers" -Drafts, edited, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1085)
      - Chapter 34, "The Great Eyrie- Shadows to the East" Clippings and pamphlets, 1955-1957 (Box 20:, Folder 1086)
      - Chapter 34, "The Great Eyrie- Shadows to the East" -Notes, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1087)
      - Chapter 34, "The Great Eyrie- Shadows to the East" Drafts, edited, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1088)
      - Final Manuscript, edited pages 1 - 65, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1089)
      - Final Manuscript, edited pages 66 - 136, undated (Box 20:, Folder 1090)
      - Final Manuscript, edited pages 137 - 204, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1091)
      - Final Manuscript, edited pages 205 - 276, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1092)
      - Final Manuscript, edited pages 277 - 362, captions, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1093)
      - Manuscript carbons- frontmatter, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1094)
      - Manuscript carbons- Chapters 1 - 10, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1095)
      - Manuscript carbons- Chapters 11 - 20, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1096)
      - Manuscript carbon, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1097)
      - "Books by" end section- draft, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1098)
      - Page proofs (Introductory pages), undated (Box 21:, Folder 1099)
      - Printer's dummy, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1100)
      - Book jacket, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1101)
      - Promotional Items, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1102)
      - Notes for promotional pamphlets, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1103)
      - Clippings and reviews, 1960-1961 (Box 21:, Folder 1104)
    - The Bees, (1961)
      - Notes & Research, 1961 September 21 (Box 21:, Folder 1105)
      - Manuscript Drafts, 1961 July - August (Box 21:, Folder 1106)
      - Correspondence, 1961 January - December (Box 21:, Folder 1107)
    - Insect Friends, (1955)
      - Notes, 1955 April 19 (Box 21:, Folder 1108A)
      - Manuscript Drafts & Correspondence, 1955 April 19 (Box 21:, Folder 1108)
      - Final Manuscript, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1109)
      - Galley, edited, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1110)
      - Page Proofs, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1111)
      - Reviews & Clippings, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1112)
    - The Thoughts of Thoreau, (1962)
      - Note Cards- unused in book?, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1113-1115)
      - Book layout/ process notes, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1116)
      - Book manuscript notes & quotes from Thoreau, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1117)
      - Reference articles, 1962 (Box 21:, Folder 1118)
      - Jacket text drafts (3), 1962 July (Box 21:, Folder 1119)
      - Biographical forward, frontmatter & contents drafts, 1962 (Box 21:, Folder 1120)
      - Drafts of introduction, undated (Box 21:, Folder 1121)
      - Manuscript drafts of "On Himself" & "On Books", undated (Box 21:, Folder 1122)
      - Page proof- 1st & 2nd, 1962 May/August (Box 21:, Folder 1123)
      - Page proofs, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1124)
      - Proof, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1125)
      - Dust jacket, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1126)
      - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 22:, Folder 1127)
    - The Strange Lives of Familiar Insects, (1962)
      - Book layout notes, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1128)
      - Notes for manuscript, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1129)
      - Reference articles, 1936-1941 (Box 22:, Folder 1130)
      - (Researched quotes) included in book, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1131)
      - Manuscript drafts (incomplete), undated (Box 22:, Folder 1132)
      - Drafts of Chapter 3: The Termite, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1133)
      - References draft, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1134)
      - Captions & Bibliography drafts, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1135)
      - Editing notes, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1136)
      - Manuscript Draft, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1137-1138)
      - Jacket sketch & Art listing, 1961 September (Box 22:, Folder 1139)
      - Proof, 1951 March (Box 22:, Folder 1140)
      - Proof of title pages, 1962 (Box 22:, Folder 1141)
      - Dust jacket, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1142)
      - Correspondence: Re: Corrections, 1963 February (Box 22:, Folder 1143)
      - Correspondence, 1945-1961 (Box 22:, Folder 1144)
    - Audubon's Wildlife, (1964)
      - Book manuscript notes, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1145)
      - Book layout/process notes, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1146)
      - Reference articles, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1147)
      - Notes from references, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1148)
      - Manuscript drafts of "Introduction" & Table of Contents, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1149)
      - Manuscript: intro & Habitats (does not include birds), undated (Box 22:, Folder 1150)
      - Chapter drafts (Intro's only), undated (Box 22:, Folder 1151)
      - Manuscript Part I, Bird chapters, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1152)
      - Manuscript Part II, Bird chapters, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1153)
      - Manuscript drafts (some incomplete) "Winter Wren", undated (Box 22:, Folder 1154)
      - Caption drafts, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1155)
      - Editor's note drafts, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1156)
      - List of illustrations, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1157)
      - Editing changes & Notes on change in illustration & captions (Richardson's Red Squirrel), undated (Box 22:, Folder 1158)
      - Complete manuscript w/ editing (Part I), undated (Box 22:, Folder 1159)
      - Complete manuscript w/ editing (Part II), undated (Box 22:, Folder 1160)
      - Captions, jacket & title pages (w/ editing), 1964 March (Box 22:, Folder 1161)
      - Proof-illustrations "Bugs", undated (Box 22:, Folder 1162)
      - Proofs (3), undated (Box 22:, Folder 1163)
      - Contract between Teale and publisher (not completed), undated (Box 22:, Folder 1164)
      - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 22:, Folder 1165)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 22:, Folder 1166)
    - Wandering Through Winter, (1965) (Box not specified)
      - Personal "to do" lists before winter trip, 1961 (Box 23:, Folder 1167)
      - Journal of expenses for trip, 1961-1962 (Box 23:, Folder 1168)
      - (12) Notebooks, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1169)
      - (12) Notebooks, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1170)
      - (12) Notebooks, 1960s (Box 23:, Folder 1171)
      - (12) Notebooks, 1960s (Box 23:, Folder 1172)
      - (12) Notebooks, 1957 (Box 23:, Folder 1173)
      - (12) Notebooks, 1957 (Box 23:, Folder 1174)
      - (8) Notebooks, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1175)
      - Notebooks, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1176)
      - "General observations from notebooks" 2 Notebooks, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1177)
      - "General observations from notebooks" 2 Notebooks, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1178)
      - Wildlife seen on the highway, 1940 July (Box 23:, Folder 1179)
      - Notes on references, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1180)
      - "Schedules" for book completion, 1963-1965 (Box 23:, Folder 1181)
      - Notes: "Things to remember when writing the winter book", 1962-1965 (Box 23:, Folder 1182)
      - Title Ideas (narrowed down), 1962 (Box 23:, Folder 1183)
      - Title Ideas, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1184)
      - Book Layout/Process Notes, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1185)
      - Postcards, 1963 (Box 23:, Folder 1186)
      - Postcard photos sent to Clara Teale, 1953 (Box 23:, Folder 1187)
      - Magazines used for research, undated (Box 23:, Folder 1188)
      - Magazines used for research, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1189)
      - Research Material, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1190)
      - Research Material, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1191)
      - Leads, Links & Endings, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1192)
      - Front Matter/Introduction (Notes & Drafts), undated (Box 24:, Folder 1193)
      - Book Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1194)
      - Page of Manuscript from Chapter XXXV (There is no published Chapter XXXV), 1963 April 10 (Box 24:, Folder 1195)
      - Journal Listings, 1963 (Box 24:, Folder 1196)
      - Journal Entries (typed & entitled by chapter 1 - 10), 1953, 1961 (Box 24:, Folder 1197)
      - Journal Entries (typed & entitled by chapter 11 - 16), 1953, 1961 (Box 24:, Folder 1198)
      - Journal Entries (typed & entitled by chapter 18 - 22), 1953, 1961 (Box 24:, Folder 1199)
      - Journal Entries (typed & entitled by chapter 23 - 28), 1953, 1961 (Box 24:, Folder 1200)
      - Journal Entries (typed & entitled by chapter 29 - 34), 1953, 1961 (Box 24:, Folder 1201)
      - Journal Entries (typed & entitled by chapter) "After Colorado," "To California," "Windy Craig," "Maine in March," "Welder Refuge," "White Sands," etc., 1953, 1961 (Box 24:, Folder 1202)
      - Chapter 1 "The Silver Strand" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1203)
      - Chapter 1 "The Silver Strand" Page drafts, 1964 (Box 24:, Folder 1204)
      - Chapter II "Gray Whales" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1205)
      - Research: Articles, pamphlets for Chapter II "Gray Whales", undated (Box 24:, Folder 1206)
      - Page Drafts of Chapter II "Gray Whales" pp. 1-9, 1963-1964 (Box 24:, Folder 1207)
      - Drafts of Chapter II "Gray Whales" (4 drafts total, 1 handwritten & incomplete), 1963 May - 1964 October (Box 24:, Folder 1208)
      - Chapter II: "Gray Whales" Correspondence, 1960 November - 1964 April (Box 24:, Folder 1209)
      - Chapter III: "Split Mountain," Research articles, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1210)
      - Chapter III: "Split Mountain," Manuscript notes, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1211)
      - Drafts of Chapter III: "Split Mountain", 1964 March (Box 24:, Folder 1212)
      - Drafts of Chapter III: "Split Mountain" (Complete drafts 1&2), 1964 (Box 24:, Folder 1213)
      - Chapter III: "Split Mountain" Correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 24:, Folder 1214)
      - Chapter IV: "The Desert Wind," Manuscript notes, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1215)
      - Chapter IV: "The Desert Wind," Research articles, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1216)
      - Drafts of Chapter IV: "The Desert Wind" pp.1-12, 1964 March (Box 24:, Folder 1217)
      - Chapter IV: "The Desert Wind" Correspondence, 1953-1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1218)
      - Manuscript notes for Chapter V, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1219)
      - Chapter V: Research articles, 1952-1962 (Box 25:, Folder 1220)
      - Drafts of Chapter V: "Snow Tires in Death Valley" pp.1 - 8, 1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1221)
      - Drafts of Chapter V: "Snow Tires in Death Valley" pp.9 - 16, 1964 January (Box 25:, Folder 1222)
      - 2 complete drafts of Chapter V: "Snow Tires...", 1964 January - August (Box 25:, Folder 1223)
      - Chapter V: Correspondence, 1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1224)
      - Chapter VI: "Rock Rainbows" Research articles, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1225)
      - Chapter VI: "Rock Rainbows" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1226)
      - Drafts of Chapter VI: "Rock Rainbows" pp.1 - 12, 1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1227)
      - Chapter VI "Rock Rainbows" complete drafts 1&2, 1964 February - September (Box 25:, Folder 1228)
      - Chapter VI: "Rock Rainbows" Correspondence, 1952-1956 (Box 25:, Folder 1229)
      - Chapter VII: "The Dripping Springs" Research articles, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1230)
      - Chapter VII: "The Dripping Springs" Correspondence, 1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1231)
      - Chapter VII: Manuscript notes, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1232)
      - Drafts of Chapter VII: "The Dripping Spring" pp. 1 - 13, 1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1233)
      - Chapter VIII: Manuscript notes, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1234)
      - Chapter VIII: Research articles, 1962 (Box 25:, Folder 1235)
      - Drafts of Chapter VIII: "Our Idle Days in Patagonia" pp. 1 - 11, 1963-1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1236)
      - Chapter VIII: "Our Idle Days in Patagonia" complete drafts 1&2, 1963 December - 1964 September (Box 25:, Folder 1237)
      - Chapter IX: Manuscript notes, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1238)
      - Chapter IX: Research articles, pamphlets, & postcards, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1239)
      - Drafts of Chapter IX: "White Dunes" pp. 1 - 9, 1964 January (Box 25:, Folder 1240)
      - Chapter IX: completed drafts 1&2, 1964 January - September (Box 25:, Folder 1241)
      - Chapter IX: Correspondence, 1953 (Box 25:, Folder 1242)
      - Chapter X: "Bitter Lake" Research articles & postcard, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1243)
      - Chapter X: "Bitter Lake" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1244)
      - Drafts of Chapter X: "Bitter Lake", 1964 June (Box 25:, Folder 1245)
      - Chapter X: completed drafts 1&2, 1964 June - October (Box 25:, Folder 1246)
      - Chapter XI: "Snow Line of the Great Plains" Research material, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1247)
      - Chapter XI: "Snow Line of the Great Plains" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1248)
      - Drafts of Chapter XI: "Snow Line of the Great Plains", 1964 May (Box 25:, Folder 1249)
      - Chapter XI: "Snow Line of the Great Plains" completed drafts 1&2, 1964 May - October (Box 25:, Folder 1250)
      - Chapter XI: "Snow Line of the Great Plains" Correspondence, 1957 July - 1964 June (Box 25:, Folder 1251)
      - Chapter XII: "Big Bend" Research material/postcards, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1252)
      - Chapter XII: "Big Bend" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1253)
      - Chapter Drafts of XII: "Big Bend" pp.1 - 16, 1964 June (Box 25:, Folder 1254)
      - Chapter XII: "Big Bend" complete drafts 1&2, 1964 June - November (Box 25:, Folder 1255)
      - Chapter XII: "Big Bend" Correspondence, 1962 (Box 25:, Folder 1256)
      - Chapter XIII: "Summer in January" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1257)
      - Chapter XIII: "Summer in January" Research articles, 1961-1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1258)
      - Page drafts of Chapter XIII: "Summer in January", 1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1259)
      - Chapter XIII: "Summer in January" complete drafts 1&2, 1964 (Box 25:, Folder 1260)
      - Chapter XIII: "Summer in January" Correspondence, 1961 (Box 25:, Folder 1261)
      - Chapter XIV: "Seventy Nine Cats" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1262)
      - Chapter XIV: "Seventy Nine Cats" Drafts, pp.1 - 7, 1963-1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1263)
      - Chapter XIV: "Seventy Nine Cats" Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1264)
      - Chapter XV: "Strange Birds Calling" Research material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1265)
      - Chapter XV: "Strange Birds Calling" manuscript notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1266)
      - Chapter XV: "Strange Birds Calling" manuscript drafts, 1964 July (Box 26:, Folder 1267)
      - Chapter XV: "Strange Birds Calling" Complete draft 1 & 2, 1964 July, September (Box 26:, Folder 1268)
      - Chapter XV: "Strange Birds Calling" Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 26:, Folder 1269)
      - Chapter XVI: "White Cranes in the Wind" Research material, 1962+ (Box 26:, Folder 1270)
      - Chapter XVI: "White Cranes in the Wind" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1271)
      - Chapter XVI: "White Cranes in the Wind" complete draft pp. 1-10, 1963 (Box 26:, Folder 1272)
      - Chapter XVI: "White Cranes in the Wind" complete draft 1 & 2, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1273)
      - Chapter XVI: "White Cranes in the Wind" Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 26:, Folder 1274)
      - Chapter XVII: "Catfish Murphree" Research Material, 1950+ (Box 26:, Folder 1275)
      - Chapter XVII: "Catfish Murphree" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1276)
      - Chapter XVII: "Catfish Murphree" chapter drafts, 1963-1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1277)
      - Chapter XVII: "Catfish Murphree" complete drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1278)
      - Chapter XVIII: "Diamond Farm" Research Material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1279)
      - Chapter XVIII: "Diamond Farm" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1280)
      - Chapter XVIII: "Diamond Farm" Drafts, pp. 1-9, 1963-1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1281)
      - Chapter XVIII: "Diamond Farm" Complete drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1282)
      - Chapter XVIII: "Diamond Farm" Correspondence, 1960+ (Box 26:, Folder 1283)
      - Chapter XIX: "Giant Beavers" Research Material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1284)
      - Chapter XIX: "Giant Beavers" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1285)
      - Chapter XIX: "Giant Beavers" Drafts pp. 1-6, 12, 1964 November (Box 26:, Folder 1286)
      - Chapter XIX: "Giant Beavers" Complete drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1287)
      - Chapter XIX: "Giant Beavers" Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1288)
      - Chapter XX: "Eagles of the Ice Jam" Research Material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1289)
      - Chapter XX: "Eagles of the Ice Jam" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1290)
      - Chapter XX: "Eagles of the Ice Jam" Drafts pp. 1-13, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1291)
      - Chapter XX: "Eagles of the Ice Jam" Manuscript drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1292)
      - Chapter XX: "Eagles of the Ice Jam" Correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1293)
      - Chapter XXI: "The White Squirrels" Research Material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1294)
      - Chapter XXI: "The White Squirrels" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1295)
      - Chapter XXI: "The White Squirrels" Drafts pp. 1-13, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1296)
      - Chapter XXI: "The White Squirrels" Complete Manuscript 1 & 2, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1297)
      - Chapter XXI: "The White Squirrels" Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 26:, Folder 1298)
      - Chapter XXII: "Return to the Stars" Research Material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1299)
      - Chapter XXII: "Return to the Stars" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1300)
      - Chapter XXII: "Return to the Stars" Drafts pp. 1-8, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1301)
      - Chapter XXII: "Return to the Stars" Complete draft 1 & 2, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1302)
      - Chapter XXII: "Return to the Stars" Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 26:, Folder 1303)
      - Chapter XXIII: "Ice Storm in Indiana" Research Material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1304)
      - Chapter XXIII: "Ice Storm in Indiana" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1305)
      - Chapter XXIII: "Ice Storm in Indiana" Drafts pp. 1-7, 1964 December (Box 26:, Folder 1306)
      - Chapter XXIII: "Ice Storm in Indiana" Complete drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1964 (Box 26:, Folder 1307)
      - Chapter XXIV: "Big Bone Lick" Research Material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1308)
      - Chapter XXIV: "Big Bone Lick" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1309)
      - Chapter XXIV: "Big Bone Lick" Drafts pp. 1-10, 1964, 1965 (Box 26:, Folder 1310)
      - Chapter XXIV: "Big Bone Lick" Complete drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1965 (Box 26:, Folder 1311)
      - Chapter XXIV: "Big Bone Lick" Correspondence, 1943-1965 (Box 26:, Folder 1312)
      - Chapter XXV: "High Water" Research Material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1313)
      - Chapter XXV: "High Water" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1314)
      - Chapter XXV: "High Water" Drafts pp. 1-9, 1965 (Box 26:, Folder 1315)
      - Chapter XXV: "High Water" Complete drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1965 (Box 26:, Folder 1316)
      - Chapter XXV: "High Water" Correspondence, 1961 September (Box 26:, Folder 1317)
      - Chapter XXVI: "Audubon's Salamanders" Research Material, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1318)
      - Chapter XXVI: "Audubon's Salamanders" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 26:, Folder 1319)
      - Chapter XXVI: "Audubon's Salamanders" Correspondence, 1960-1965 (Box 26:, Folder 1320)
      - Chapter XXVI: "Audubon's Salamanders" Drafts pp. 1 - 11, 1965 January (Box 27:, Folder 1321)
      - Chapter XXVI: "Audubon's Salamanders" Complete drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1322)
      - Chapter XXVII: "The White Forest" Drafts pp. 1 - 11, 1963-1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1323)
      - Chapter XXVII: "The White Forest" Post Cards & reference articles, ca. 1960 (Box 27:, Folder 1324)
      - Chapter XXVII: "The White Forest" Manuscript notes, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1325)
      - Chapter XXVII: "The White Forest" Correspondence, 1956+ (Box 27:, Folder 1326)
      - Chapter XXVIII: "Snowflake Country" Research Material, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1327)
      - Chapter XXVIII: "Snowflake Country" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1328)
      - Chapter XXVIII: "Snowflake Country" Drafts, 1963-1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1329)
      - Chapter XXVIII: "Snowflake Country" Complete drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1330)
      - Chapter XXVIII: "Snowflake Country" Correspondence, 1957-1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1331)
      - Chapter XXIX: "Night in the Sugarbush" Research Material, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1332)
      - Chapter XXIX: "Night in the Sugarbush" manuscript notes, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1333)
      - Chapter XXIX: "Night in the Sugarbush" drafts, 1963, 1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1334)
      - Chapter XXIX: "Night in the Sugarbush" Manuscript drafts 1, 2 & 3, 1963, 1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1335)
      - Chapter XXX: "The Witch Hazel Gatherer" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1336)
      - Chapter XXX: "The Witch Hazel Gatherer" Research Articles, 1946-1964 (Box 27:, Folder 1337)
      - Chapter XXX: "The Witch Hazel Gatherer" Drafts pp. 1 - 11, complete draft, 1964-1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1338)
      - Chapter XXXI: "The Great Swamp" Research Material, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1339)
      - Chapter XXXI: "The Great Swamp" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1340)
      - Chapter XXXI: "The Great Swamp" Drafts pp. 1 - 11, 1963, 1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1341)
      - Chapter XXXI: "The Great Swamp" Complete drafts 1 & 2, 1963, 1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1342)
      - Chapter XXXI: "The Great Swamp" Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 27:, Folder 1343)
      - Chapter XXXII: "The Deer Yard" Research Articles & Notes, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1344)
      - Chapter XXXII: "The Deer Yard" Notes, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1345)
      - Chapter XXXII: "The Deer Yard" Drafts, 1963, 1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1346)
      - Chapter XXXII: "The Deer Yard" Correspondence, 1961 (Box 27:, Folder 1347)
      - Chapter XXXIII: "Coast of the High Tides" Reference Articles, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1348)
      - Chapter XXXIII: "Coast of the High Tides" Maps, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1349)
      - Chapter XXXIII: "Coast of the High Tides" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1350)
      - Chapter XXXIII: "Coast of the High Tides" drafts pp. 1 - 10, 1965 March (Box 27:, Folder 1351)
      - Chapter XXXIII: "Coast of the High Tides" Correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 27:, Folder 1352)
      - Chapter XXXIV: "North of Caribou" Research Articles, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1353)
      - Chapter XXXIV: "North of Caribou" Manuscript Notes, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1354)
      - Chapter XXXIV: "North of Caribou" Drafts pp. 1 - 7, 1963, 1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1355)
      - Chapter XXXIV: "North of Caribou" final draft, 1965 April 10 (Box 27:, Folder 1356)
      - Chapter Envelopes with notes by EWT, 1963-1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1357)
      - Chapter Envelopes with notes by EWT, 1963-1965 (Box 27:, Folder 1358)